Julián Lopez Baasch

{Data Scientist, Economist} Av. Libertador 5386, Buenos Aires, Argentina +54-911-6267-7072 julianlopezba@gmail.com

PRINCIPAL INTERESTS

I am an economist and data scientist who loves building products based on machine learning and deep learning. Also, I have skills in NLP, information retrieval and Computer Vision. As to my research interests, I am interested in understanding the dynamics in society using artificial agents that interact in a game-theoretic setting. Thus, I found in MARL methods a natural fit for my interests.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

M.Sc. Intelligent Systems

2019

AIML GROUP, Universitat Pompeu Fabra, Barcelona, Spain

- Research in Multi Agent Reinforcement Learning under direction of prof. Martí Sànchez-Fibla.
- Dissertation title: Estimating loss aversion in human behavioral data: A Bayesian approach using Reinforcement Learning.
- Coursework: Machine Learning, Autonomous Systems, Pattern Recognition, Natural Language Interaction, Computer Vision, Web Intelligence, Data Driven Social Network Analysis

M.Sc. Economics 2014

Universidad Torcuato Di Tella, Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Focus areas: Numerical Methods and Game Theory.
- Research in quantitative finance under direction of prof. Nicolás Merener.
- Coursework: Real Analysis, Measure Theory, Dynamic Programming, Evolutionary Game Theory, Causal Inference, Social and Economic Networks, Stochastic Calculus applied to Finance

Licenciate in Economics

2011

Universidad Torcuato Di Tella, Buenos Aires, Argentina

• Minor in Mathematics and Satistics.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

EMPLOYMENT Data Scientist Specialist

2021 - Present

Bimo, Buenos Aires, Argentina

Bimo is a fintech startup that is redefining the future of digital wallets. Here, I am responsible of defining the data strategy and machine learning solutions that will help the company meet its business goals.

Machine Learning Consultant

2019 - Present

mGrana, Buenos Aires, Argentina

As a freelance data scientist, I've assisted to a micro-lending fintech startup with:

- Feature engineering and integration of features into the machine learning pipeline.
- Building an NLP based clustering model of mobile text data points.

Sr. Data Scienitst 2019 - 2021

Banco galicia, Buenos Aires, Argentina

• Led a data science team with the goal of designing, executing, and delivering data products using company data and third-party sources.

- Trained and deployed NLP models for multi-class and multi-label classification of comments and posts in social networks (Twitter, Instagram, and Facebook). Served this model through a RESTful API for leveraging opinion mining of customers on own and third-party channels.
- Web Scraping of main e-commerce platforms in Latin America which generated sales leads on a daily basis.
- Developed and deployed a model for fraudulent users detection in social networks, based on profile picture and description similarity.

Data Analyst 2014 - 2017

DIRECTV Latin America, Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Responsible for implementing analytical solutions to various datadriven problems related to Customer Experience regional office.
- Developed a model for measuring repeated TV content between channels based on Jaccard Index.
- Implemented a predictive model of prepaid recharges based on media, sports and social events.
- Deployed a logistic regression model to predict the level of satisfaction based on the customer journey records.

TEACHING (at Universidad Di Tella)

• Undergrad TA in Law and Economics

Prepared text materials for 'Law and Economics' course, BS in Economics. Helped +30 students gain a better understanding of the practical exercises and theory. Assisted group study in the problem sets solving.

SKILLS

• Machine Learning, Deep Learning, NLP, Computer Vision, Deployment, REST-ful API, Web Scraping, Leadership

STACK

- Languages:
 - Python, Pytorch, TensorFlow, Keras
- Framework: Flask, Docker, AWS
- Databases:

MySQL, PostgreSQL, Hadoop, Hive, Spark

• Other

SNAP, Networkx, Matlab, OpenCV, javascript